Okay, so now we've prepared the bat.
We've turned our pot top over and it's time to make sure that this is properly on center so that we can start trimming.
And the way we are going to do this is with a pin tool, and I showed you earlier.
Now, what I'm going to do is turn the plant pot on the wheel and take my pin tool and steady my hands up and let the pin tool touch the pot.
Now as you can see, the pin tool is making a mark, that to there.
Now what I do with this mark, I face it towards me, I put a finger on each side of our mark, it's right there and right there and I'm simply going to push the pot away from me and then I'm going to re-check.
Okay, so you can see right there, the navel is pretty much going, making a full circle around the pot.
The more of center the pot will be, the smaller your line will be.
So if it's really off-center, I'll just be touching one little side of it.
So now we have the pot centered on the wheel, the next thing is going to be securing it and I just want to get a little bit of moisture on this wheel so that clay will stick.
You dried it off again, similar way with the towel.
There's no too much water.
Now I'm going to take some scrap clay here, simply take some pieces and take them around the edges of the plant pot.
Usually I only need three, this is quite a large pot, some larger pot require more.
Notice how I'm not sticking the clay to the plant pot.
I'm sticking it to the back.
I'm just using one edge of the clay to secure the edge of the plant pot into place.
Okay, so now we have centered and secured our plant pot.
The next thing is going to be trimming the foot and I will talk about that next.